911調度中心  佛羅里達州 塔拉哈西
911 請問您有什麼緊急情況?
911. What's your emergency?
- 女士 請冷靜 - 是的 先生 我們的人已經在路上了
- Ma'am,you need to calm down. - Yes,sir,we have units on the way.
請不要掛電話 告訴我你的全名
Please stay on the line with me and give me your full name.
請隨時準備好 2-5區塊警員 報警人還在電話上
Stand by,charlie 2-5, i still have the complainant on the line.
911 請問您有什麼緊急情況?
911. What's your emergency?
女士 警察正在敲門
Ma'am,the police are knocking on the door right now.
- 911 請問您有什麼緊急情況? - 是的 門口是真的警察
- 911. What is your emergency? - Yes,that is a real police officer outside.
911 請問您有什麼緊急情況?
911. What's your emergency?
女士 請冷靜下來 不要叫
Ma'am,you need to calm down and stop yelling.
是的 先生 我們的人已經在路上了
Yes,sir,we have a unit on the way.
請不要掛電話 請說出你的全名
Please stay on the line. Please give me your full name.
911 請問您有什麼緊急情況?
911. What's your emergency?
倉庫埵陪茼漱H
There's a dead body in the warehouse.
您說什麼 先生?
Excuse me,sir?
克勞福德維爾的倉庫埵陪茼漱H
There's a dead body in the warehouse in crawfordville.
能說明倉庫的詳細位置嗎?
Can you be more specific about the location of that warehouse?
克勞福德維爾高速西面 伍德蘭南面
West of crawfordville highway, south of woodland.
一條泥路上
A dirt road.
有地址嗎?
Do you have an address?
沒有
No.
44區塊警員 請查明疑發現屍體的位置
Charlie 44,role to location of possible dead body.
派人來了嗎?
Is someone on the way?
是的 但請不要掛電話 先生
Yes,but i need you to stay on the line with me,sir.
您確定那人已經死了嗎 先生?
Are you sure the victim is dead,sir?
- 馬上就要死了 - 您說什麼?
- He will be in a second. - Excuse me?
先生? 先生!
Sir? Sir!
44區塊警員 聽到槍擊聲 重複一次 聽到槍擊聲
Charlie 44, we have shots fired now. I repeat,shots fired.
我不知道發生了什麼事
I'm not sure what's going on in there,
已經和報警人失去聯繫
but i no longer have contact with the complainant.
建議加強警惕
Advise and use extreme caution.
我是44區塊警員 我們到了
This is charlie 44. We're on scene.
門口很安靜 我們現在進去
It's quiet out front. We're moving in.
收到 請小心 救護人員已經在路上了
10-4. Use caution. Ems is on the way,too.
注意了 Ray
Eyes open,ray.
警察!
State police!
警察! 請開門!
State police! Open the door!
警察!
Police!
喂 椅子上的!
You,in the chair!
站起來 舉起手來
Stand up and let me see your hands.
最後說一次 夥計! 站起來!
Last chance,man! Stand up!
我的老天爺吶
Lord have mercy.
- 別把晚飯給吐光了 Ray - 我沒事
- Do not blow dinner,ray. - I'm ok.
說真的 你想出去 就出去吧
I mean it. You need to outside,you go.
都說了我沒事
I said i'm fine.
我是Charlie 44  不用派救護人員來了 調度中心
This is charlie 44. You can cancel that ems out here, dispatch.
你確定 44?
Are you sure,44?
是的 我確定 看樣子是自殺身亡
Oh,yeah,i'm sure. This looks to be a successful suicide.
收到
10-4.
什麼鬼東西
What the hell.
找到開關了
Got a light.
噢 夥計 看看這個 Tommy
Oh,man,take a look at this,tommy.
這些女人都死了?
These women all dead?
這位好像沒被找到
Doesn't say this one's every been found.
我記得那名字
I recognize that name.
她3星期前剛失蹤
She only went missing 3 weeks ago.
還是44呼叫
This is 44 again.
請馬上叫頭兒 警探 犯罪現場人員過來...
Uh,we're gonna need bosses,detectives, crime scene out here on the double.
那個 還是...
Ah,hell,just...
叫大家都來吧
Send everybody.
跟我說說這裙子
Tell me what the dress is about.
嘿 週末愉快 JJ
Hey,have a good weekend,jj.
抱歉
Sorry.
我租的海濱別墅泡湯了
There goes my beach house rental.
還有我那無法退款的 大西洋城"拼罪"牌局週末行
And my non-refundable sin to win weekend in atlantic city.
- "贏了就有罪"? (字面意思) - 是滴
- Sin to win? - Yeah.
我總能贏很多
And i always win big.
我沒啥安排
I didn't have any plans.
嘿 這是我剛收到的傳真
Hey,uh,these were just faxed to me.
我同塔拉哈西 負責失蹤女學生案子的警探談過
I talked to a tallahassee detective who's been working a missing coed--
Rebecca Daniels 3周前在 佛羅里達州立大學附近慢跑時失蹤
rebecca daniels-- she went missing while jogging near the fsu campus 3 weeks ago.
他是誰?
Who's this?
佛羅里達州警1個半小時前 接到的自殺案
Florida state police responded to an apparent suicide an hour and a half ago.
中年男子 這些是他死後拍下的照片
Middle-aged male. Those are photos of him postmortem.
紋身是怎麼回事?
What's with the tattoos?
是的 他身上都是 幾乎紋滿全身
Yeah,he's covered in them, almost completely.
因為這個 他們想請我們出馬
That's why they requested our presence.
紋身圖案是之前失蹤的女性
The tattoos are portraits of previously missing women,
有多年前遇害的 有後來發現遺骸的
with the years of death or the years the remains were recovered,anyway.
紋身和屍體旁邊牆壁上貼的人物對應
The tattoos correlate to faces on a wall next to the body,
附有她們的信息  最早可追溯到10年前
with information on the women going back 10 years.
Rebecca的資料也貼在牆上 但沒有紋在屍體上
Rebecca is also shown on that wall, but there's no image of her on the body.
警探們認為 也許她還活著
The detective thinks that that may mean that she's alive somewhere.
- 他打電話報警自殺的對吧?  - 是的 你怎麼...
- He called in his own suicide,didn't he? - Yeah.How did you--
他自導自演的
he staged all this.
沒理由演一齣沒人看的戲
No reason to put on a show without an audience.
叫他們不要動屍體
Tell them to leave the body where it is.
我們得看看 他想展示什麼給大家看
We need to see it exactly how he wanted it seen.
如果這女孩還活著  唯一知道她藏身之處的人可能已經死了
If this girl's still out there, the only one who knows where she is may be dead.
犯罪心理 第五季 第20集 千言萬語
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode20 A Thousand Words
"一個真誠的藝術家 會盡力創作有生命的作品"
"A sincere artist tries to create something which is in itself a living thing."
澳洲畫家 威廉·多貝爾
painter william dobell.
酷熱難當啊
Oh,this heat is brutal.
不只是高溫 濕度也夠悶人
You know,it isn't so much the heat as it is the humidity.
不管是什麼原因 反正就是糟糕
At some point it doesn't matter how you look at it. It all sucks.
- FBI? - 是的
- Fbi? - Yes,sir.
嗨 我是John Barton 塔拉哈西警察
Hi,john barton, tallahassee pd.
我是Rebecca Daniels失蹤案的負責人
I'm the primary on the missing girl,rebecca daniels.
如果你們需要 案卷就放在我車
I got my files in the car if you need them.
我是Hotchner探員 這位是Rossi探員 Prentiss探員 Reid博士 Morgan和Jareau探員
I'm agent hotchner. This is agent rossi, agent prentiss, dr. Reid,agent morgan, agent jareau.
我們通過電話
Yeah,we spoke on the phone.
是的 嘿 謝謝你們這麼快就趕來了 非常感激
Yeah,hey,thanks a lot for coming out so quickly. I appreciate that.
我確定所有的遇害女性都來自西南部...
I've also confirmed that all the women are victims from around the southeast--
佛羅里達 路易斯安納 喬治亞州 阿拉巴馬
florida,louisiana, georgia,alabama.
Rebecca是唯一沒有紋在他身上的女性
And rebecca's the only woman on the wall who's not represented on his body?
是的 只有她
Yeah,she's the only one.
但願你們的胃夠堅強
Hope you have a strong stomach.
椅子是背著的? 你們找到他時就這樣?
The chair was turned like that? This is exactly where you found him?
是的
Yeah.
- 自導自演啊 - 自負得很啊
- Talk about staging. - Talk about ego.
還有幾箱日記和作文書
There's also a couple boxes with journals or composition books.
堶掉g滿了東西
They're filled with writing.
那些只取了指紋 還沒看過
We haven't been through them yet other than to dust them for prints.
查出他的身份了嗎?
Have you identified him?
正在查 已經催了DNA和指紋的偵查
We're working on it. Uh,we got a rush on the dna and the prints.
他不是當地人 查閱全國記錄需要點時間
He's cleared locally, but it's gonna take some time to get the national records.
財產記錄呢?
What about property records?
和房東談過了
Talked to the owner.
她說幾周前租給一個叫Bob傢伙 長相一般 人很文靜
She said she rented it a couple weeks ago to a quiet,normal-looking guy named bob.
他說想存放一些設備 而且付了現金
He said he wanted to store some equipment, and he paid in cash.
他們總跟常人無異
They're always normal.
- 沒有租約嗎? - 沒 月結的
- No lease? - Uh,month to month,no.
我們這窮鄉僻壤 別期望我們文件記錄完整
Out here in the boonies you don't get a lot of,uh, record-keeping types.
尤其涉及到現金交易 我敢打賭沒有
Especially when it comes to cash transactions,i'll bet.
他年紀不小了 但失蹤人口記錄只能追溯10年嗎?
He's no kid,yet the missings go back only 10 years?
- 我們能查到的就是 - 大器晚成啊
- As far as i could tell. - Late bloomer.
你們見過很多嗎? 這種傢伙自殺的場面?
You see this a lot,uh, these guys killing themselves?
大多數連環殺手會在被抓後 在監獄自殺
Most serial killers who commit suicide do it in prison after they're caught.
JJ 盡可能收集之前的受害者的資料
Jj,gather as much information about the prior victims as you can.
Morgan和Prentiss 分析日記
Morgan and prentiss, take the journals.
Dave 你跟Reid研究紋身 看能否發現Daniels藏身地的線索
Dave,you and reid, the tattoos. See if he left any clues about where miss daniels might be.
你覺得她可能還活著嗎?
You think there's a chance she might still be alive?
還是別猜測為好
It's probably better not to speculate.
我能看下關於Daniels的失蹤案檔嗎?
May i take a look at the case files you have on miss daniels?
可以 當然 沒問題
Yeah,yeah,no problem.
他一邊跟接線員說話 突然就開了槍
He was on the phone with dispatch and then, boom.
這有多高 15英尺 (4.5米)?
Must be what,15 feet?
完美的謝幕啊
Consummate overachiever.
對 是的
Right. Right.
為何男人自殺時會把血濺得到處都是?
Why is it when men kill themselves, itets everywhere,
而女人從來不會搞成如此?
but women don't leave a mess, like they were never there?
女人比較擔心清掃的問題 男人則無所顧忌
Women worry about who has to clean up. Men don't give a damn.
JJ 有發現嗎?
Jj,what have you found?
最早的剪報是10年前的 按時間順序排列 直到最近
The earliest clipping is from 10 years ago, and they're in order, oldest to newest.
Brenda Carlyle是第一個 Rebecca Daniels是最後一個
Brenda carlyle first, rebecca daniels last.
行為縝密
That was thoughtful of him.
10年以來每年都有一名受害者
One victim a year for 10 years straight.
每個女孩的遺體 都會在旅客常去的林區被發現
Each girl's remains were recovered in a well-traveled wooded area.
勒死 多次性侵犯 然後大約一周後 另一名女子失蹤
Strangled,repeatedly sexually assaulted, and then about a week later, another woman goes missing.
有沒有綁架事件發生在 屍體發現之前的?
Did the new abductions happen before the previous body's been found?
- 沒 從來沒有 - 所以他的作案週期是一年
- No,never. - So he has a year-long cycle.
他玩膩了她們 然後再換個新的
He uses them up and he gets a newer model.
但直到前一個女孩的屍體被發現前 他不會掠走新的女孩
But he won't take another girl until the last body's been found.
他像是在講故事  想說個新的 就必須把老的講完
He's telling a story and he can't start a new one until the old one's over.
看這個 在16世紀末17世紀初期
Look at that.At the turn of the 16th century,
被處死刑的男囚會被紋上玫瑰紋身
rose tattoos were put on men who were sentenced to death.
- 真的嗎? - 是 如果他們越獄 就可以據此識別
- Really? - Yeah. If they escaped, it served to identify them.
但現在玫瑰象徵著純潔的愛
But now roses pretty much symbolize pure love.
純潔的愛 直到動手殺死她們
Pure love. Right before he kills them.
- 嘿 讀過"圖案人"嗎? (著名科幻小說) - 沒
- Hey,have you read "the illustrated man"? - Nope.
很棒的 是雷·布萊伯利 (科幻大師) 值得收藏的短篇小說
Oh,it's amazing. It's a collection of short stories by ray bradbury,
講述一名全身覆蓋著紋身的男子 而紋身是由未來的女人設計的
based on the metafictive device of a man who's covered in tattoos drawn by a woman from the future.
每到晚上紋身圖案就會復活 並講述一段故事 真的很贊
At nighttime, the tattoos come to life and tell a story. It's pretty awesome.
這些確實是在講述故事
These do tell a story.
你一定還想看這個
Oh,you want to see something?
紋身樹中的一處空白
A space in the tree.
這個旁邊沒有日期
And there's no date on that one.
他為何要留著這處空白?
Why would he leave that space blank?
也許這傢伙只是個神經病
Maybe this guy's just a psycho.
真這麼簡單 那我們就失業了
If it were that simple, we'd all be out of a job.
Reid
Hey,reid.
怎麼了?
What's up?
這傢伙留下的日記還挺長
Our man here was a prolific journaler.
而且字跡密密麻麻
With teeny tiny handwriting.
他可能在接受某些心理輔導 日記是療法的一部分
He probably had counseling at some point when journaling was part of his therapy.
我們也這麼想
That's what we were thinking.
直說吧?
And?
你知道 我們兩個人就是讀三天也讀不完
And,uh, well,you know, the two of us, it would take us like 3 days to read all of this stuff.
你們欠我一次
You guys owe me.
難怪沒有人把這些案件聯繫起來
It's no wonder no one has ever connected these cases.
死者來自不同的州 隸屬不同的司法管轄區
They're from different states, different jurisdictions.
這絕非偶然 他非常瞭解司法系統
It's probably no accident. He knows the system.
那現在為何自殺? 根本沒人追查到他
Why kill himself now? He wasn't on anyone's radar.
一定有什麼發生了轉變 讓大家集合
Something changed. Let's gather everyone.
到目前為止我們都有什麼線索?
So what do we know so far?
他希望警方發現這 也希望我們能夠看到這一切
He wanted the police here. He wanted us to see all this.
他絕對是一個虐待狂 我們發現他的日記有中詳細圖畫
He was definitely a sadist. From what we saw, his journals were graphic and meticulous.
用受害者肖像覆滿全身 顯示出他很有條理 很有佔有慾
Covering himself with his victims' likeness is methodical,possessive.
他將永遠擁有她們
He'll always own them.
自殺更像是一種承諾
And the suicide shows commitment.
他非常有組織 有強迫性 作案週期為一年
He's organized and compulsive. The crimes are on an annual cycle.
板上的打印資料 都是在2周前的同一天被打印出的
Computer printouts on the board, they were all printed on the same day-- 2 weeks ago.
他那個時候租用了這個建築
That's when he rented this building.
然後把所有東西都陳列其中 他的犯罪歷史
And proceeded to move everything into it. It's a history of his crimes.
他在兩周內安排了這一切
So he did all of this in 2 weeks.
作案十年 無人追查他 本可繼續隱身的
He got away with it for 10 years. He could have kept going.
但他決定結束這一切 並全部呈現給我們
But he decides to end it all and hand everything to us.
- 就是這樣 所有一切 - Reid?
- That's it--everything.Everything. - Reid?
所有的一切 他的身體 紋身 剪報 打印資料和日記
Everything. His body, the tattoos,the clippings, the printout,the journals.
他把所有東西都搬到這個房間 他希望我們看到這一切
He moved it all into one room. He wanted us to see all of it.
看到他的一切 他的傑作  按時間排列的那些受害女人
See all of him-- his work--the women,he put them in chronological order.
- 他像在炫耀 "看我牛不" - 我們明白這點
- He's screaming,"look at me." - We all got that.
不 仔細想想 退一步想 似乎有道理啊
No,but think about it. If you take a step back, it sort of makes sense.
不過是一份供詞 一份誇張的供詞
It's just a confession. A giant,flashy confession.
警方都沒有察覺呢 不明嫌犯為何要自首?
What would we say if an unsub turned himself in to the police before they were even onto him?
- 他想掩蓋什麼東西 - 或者什麼人
- That he was trying to hide something. - Or someone.
他在第三本書中犯了一個錯誤 我差點忽略 但後來發現了它
He made a mistake-- in his third book. I almost missed it, but then i caught it.
"我本以為需要更久 但今天是個幸運日"
"I thought it would take longer, "but today was the lucky day.
"她正好經過... 幾乎錯過了她"
"She almost walked right by, "almost missed her completely,
"但在最後時刻 我們找到了我們的新客人"
"but at the last moment, we found our latest guest."
- "我們" - 他還有個搭檔
- We. - He has a partner.
他把一切都展示在這 好讓我們不再繼續查案 挖掘更深
He put everything in this room so we wouldn't look further, wouldn't dig even deeper.
如果他有搭檔 那他仍然隱匿在外 並且抓了Rebecca Daniels
If he has a partner, he's still out there, and he's got rebecca daniels.
對不起 很抱歉
Oh,i'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
我大聲喊過 但我想你的音樂太大聲
I was calling out, but i guess your music was too loud.
- 你沒事吧? - 我沒事 很好
- Are you all right? - I'm fine. It's all right.
- Juliet Monroe? - 是我
- Juliet monroe? - That's me.
這是你的 請簽名
That's for you. If i can get you to sign here.
- 非常感謝 不好意思 - 沒事
- Thank you very much. Sorry about that. - It's fine.
- 祝你愉快 - 你也是
- Have a great day,now. - You,too.
夫人
Ma'am.
我的至愛 當你讀到這封信時 我已經不在了
My dearest love, by the time you read this, i will have gone.
你帶給我如此幸福的人生 像我這樣的男人 是從未奢望過的
Our life together has brought me more joy than a man like me thought he could ever know.
我本想帶著你跟我一起走
My first wish would be to take you with me,
但我知道你已經做好準備 展開人生新的篇章
but since you are in our home readying yourself with the next chapter of our life--
養育我們可愛的寶寶
to care for and raise our beautiful child,
我別無所求 只希望你能完成我們共同的使命
my last hope is that you finish what we started.
求你 求求你
Please. Please.
讓我回家吧
Just let me go home.
這是你的錯
This is your fault.
這全是你的錯
求你了
Please.
她在那邊幹什麼?
What's she doing down there?
跟媒體溝通 讓他們別馬上報道這件事
She's trying to keep the media from running the story right now.
媒體報道對我們應該有利呀? 能給他的搭檔施加壓力
But wouldn't that help us get it out there, put some pressure on the partner?
如果搭檔不知道他自殺了 或許會因為失去Daniel而離開
But if the partner didn't know about the suicide, he might dispose of miss daniels and disappear.
只有JJ能說服媒體停止報道
If anyone can stop the media from running something,it's jj.
我們側寫一下這個搭檔吧
So let's profile the partner.
我們知道 不明嫌犯具有支配性人格 是主導者
We know that the unsub was a dominant personality, an alpha.
在一起案件中 主犯為了保護從犯而自殺
Can any of you guys think of a case where a dominant unsub committed suicide
- 大家遇到過相同的情況嗎? - 沒有
- to protect a submissive partner? - No.
所以從犯一定在某些方面和主犯是平等的 至少他們彼此不是敵手
So the partner must be an equal in some way, or at least not a competitor,
他不需要在這個人身上實現自己的統治欲
not somebody that he needed to feel dominance over.
或許是一個他在乎的人?
Maybe it was someone he cared about?
對一個殘酷成性的精神病來說 很難去在乎什麼人
It would be hard for a sadistic psychopath to care about anybody.
正是因此 這個同夥對他才那麼重要
Which would make the partner all that much more important to him.
那些畫紋身的呢? 他不可能自己紋上去
What about the tattoo artist? He couldn't have done those by himself.
- 或許同夥就是扮演這個角色 - 畫紋身當然重要了
- Maybe that's the role for the partner. - It would certainly make him important.
這些跟Becky究竟有什麼關係?
What the hell does any of this have to do with becky?
我們不該採取些行動嗎? 該死
I mean,isn't there something we should be doing,damn it?
警探 借一步說話
Detective,may i speak with you for a moment?
我們可以撐到6點的晚間新聞
So we have until the evening news--6 P.M.
他們知道多少?
How much do they know?
那些警察把所有事情都說了
Oh,the troopers told them everything.
Rossi探員 你打電話來 是為了告訴我案子已經解決了嗎?
Agent rossi, please tell me you called because the case is over
我就可以把這些噁心的圖片 從我的超美桌面上清除了
and i can erase this freakity-freak off my otherwise uber-delicious desktops.
離破案還早著呢 孩子
Long way to go,kid.
我對表皮藝術的變態行為 見識也不少了 但是這傢伙...
I am into epidermartistry as much as the next gen xer, but this guy.
很慶幸你們不用跟他呼吸一樣的空氣了 我親愛的朋友
Eesh, i'm just glad he's not breathing the same air as you, my fine furry friends.
是啊 刺青師有什麼發現嗎?
Agreed. What have you found out about tattoo artists down here?
佛州的刺青師都需要有上崗執照
That the state of florida requires licensing for all skin illustrators,
但是...我就不詳細說我是怎麼知道的了...
but--and i am not going to elaborate on how i know this--
並不是所有人都經過了官方認可
not everyone in the body art lifestyle goes through official channels.
我們就先從有執照的開始 看有沒有人能認出這是誰的作品
All right,we'll start with the legit ones and see if anyone recognizes the work.
- 我會把清單發到你的PDA上 - 謝了
- I shall send the list to your pda. - Thanks.
表皮藝術?
Epidermartistry?
只有一個女孩 能填滿那股能量...
Only a girl can fill that empty energy.
抱歉我話說得難聽 只是太累了
Look,i'm sorry i popped off. I'm just a little worked up.
我看了Rebecca Daniels的卷宗 是你的報告
I've been over the rebecca daniels case file,your reports.
- 你認識她嗎? - 什麼?
- Do you know her? - What?
你們有什麼私人關係嗎?
Is there a personal relationship?
你到底想說什麼?
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
你兩次叫她"Becky"
You've referred to her twice as becky.
是嗎?
I did?
別處報告都不會這麼叫 都稱她"Rebecca"
And nowhere else is she referred to that way. It's always rebecca.
如果有什麼事會阻礙你的判斷 你必須告訴我
Now,if there's something that's gonna cloud your judgment, i need to know about it.
不 我不認識她
No. I don't know her.
那是怎麼回事?
Then what is it?
聽著 我...我幹這一行已經很長時間了
Look,i've... I've been doing this a long time,and...
整天面對這些事情 人們互相殘殺 一起墮落 你明白嗎?
It usually just washes right over me,you know, people killing people, depravity,you know?
晚上一個人在家 就會想起來
As long as you make it home at night,right?
但是這個人...她的父母...
But this one... Her parents...
他們都是很善良很體面的人
They're just such good, decent people.
她是一個好女孩 而且...
She seems like an amazing girl,and...
沒什麼了
It's all.
有時候就是難以承受
Sometimes it's just too much.
會摻雜私人感情在堶
You take it personal.
很愚蠢 是吧?
Stupid,right?
如果你是不計後果地去關心他們 那才叫愚蠢
Caring about a victim, personalizing them, can only be stupid if it's reckless.
沒擔心我了 我沒事的
Don't worry about me. I'm good.
那就好 走吧 但願能送她回家
All right. Let's go and try to bring her home.
外面都快40度了吧 可和倉庫比起來 還是跟冰櫃似的
It's like 110 out here and it feels like a refrigerator compared to their warehouse.
Reid看得怎麼樣了?
How's reid doing?
高溫根本不足以困擾他
It doesn't even seem to faze him.
他就待在角落 翻看日記
He's just sitting there in a corner turning pages.
是啊 他閱讀的時候 心就鑽到堶悼h了
Yeah,he goes to another place when he reads.
我拿到了塔拉哈西大部分刺青館的地址
I've got the addresses of the major tattoo parlors in tallahassee.
那幅作品刺得非常仔細啊 說不定有人會認出來
That work is pretty detailed. Someone might recognize it.
你要和我一起去確認嗎?
You want to go check these out with me?
好啊
Sounds fun.
媒體那邊又爭取到了幾小時
Hey,so,uh,i got a few more hours out of the media.
有什麼線索就查什麼
Well,we'll take what we can get.
Prentiss和Rossi去調查刺青館了
Prentiss and rossi are going to check out some tattoo parlors.
- 他還好嗎? - 還好
- Is he ok? - Yeah.
你問過他為什麼叫她Becky了嗎?
Did you ask him about calling her becky?
- 他會沒事的 - 希望如此
- He'll be all right. - Well,i hope so.
現在根本沒有那姑娘是否還活著的線索
Because we still have no indication that this girl's even alive.
我沒法完成所有的事
I wasn't able to tie up all the loose ends.
你應該知道發生了什麼
You would have known what was happening.
所以 該由你來善後了
So now it's left for you.
等到晚上 將它帶到水邊
Wait for night and take it to the water.
剩下的 就讓動物去做吧
The animals will do the rest.
是他殺了這些女人?
This guy killed all those women?
看起來是這樣 現在還有一個女人失蹤
Looks like it. And there's another one missing.
然後他自殺了?
Then he killed himself?
- 是啊 - 不錯 也算是一種公共服務吧
- Yeah,he did. - Good. Sort of a public service.
也許這樣想 大家都會好過一點
I guess that's a good way of looking at it.
我們把屍體遞交塔拉哈西的殮房 你簽字嗎?
We send it to the M.E. 'S office in tallahassee. You sign it?
- 我晚點再處理這事 謝謝 - 多謝
- I'll take care of that,later. Thanks. - Thanks a lot.
你確定可以挪屍體了?
You sure it's ok to move the body?
嗯 沒理由不挪啊  這傢伙的表演我們已經看了
Well,there's no reason not to anymore. We've seen this guy's show.
你以前見過像這樣的事情嗎?
Have you ever seen anything like this before?
- 像哪樣? - 一切
- Like what? - Everything.
呃...自殺 剪報 日記...
The,uh,suicide, the clippings, the journal.
我想 應該可以說  沒人曾見過這樣的事情
I think it's pretty safe to say that no one's ever seen anything like this.
夥計 這活幹得可真漂亮
Man,this is beautiful work.
紋一身衣服唄? 他紋全了嗎?
It's a body suit? He's completely covered?
- 差不多吧 - 沒錯
- Pretty much. - Yeah.
- "圖案人" - 今天我是第二次聽到這個了
- "the illustrated man." - Second time i've heard that today.
- 那本書? - Reid提到過
- The book? - Reid mentioned it.
在紋身行 那個故事可是人盡皆知啊
Everybody in the body art world knows that story.
這夥計自殺了?
You said this dude killed himself?
他...是割腕了還是怎麼的?
Did he,like, gash his wrists open or something?
這紋身...你能認出是誰紋的嗎?
The tattoos--could you recognize who did this?
我倒想 我會立刻雇下他  這看上去像是徒手紋的
I wish. I'd hire this dude in a heartbeat. This looks free-hand.
相信我 徒手在皮膚上紋肖像 是相當難的 夥計
Trust me,free-hand portraiture is pretty gnarly to do on skin,man.
他是舉槍自盡的吧? 因為這些照片都沒有拍到頭
Did he shoot himself? Because none of these pictures have a head.
你能分辨出 這些是否 出自同一個紋身師之手?
Can you tell if the same artist did these?
看起來像是 但並不是在同一時間紋的
It looks like it. But they weren't all done at the same time.
有些墨跡比較新
Some of the inks are newer.
要是我看到屍體 也許能告訴你們更多信息
You know,if i saw the body, i'd probably be able to tell you more.
這些呢?
How about these?
肖像真不少呢 代表什麼意義嗎?
These are a lot of portraits. What do they mean?
這正是我們試圖要搞清楚的
That's what we're trying to figure out.
等等 這個不配套啊
Wait. That doesn't fit.
什麼不配套?
What doesn't?
這玫瑰下面有圖案
There's something under the rose there.
看著像...十字? 挺大一個
Looks like... A cross? A big one.
- 哪? - 在玫瑰堶
- Where? - Inside the rose.
這個就紋得很糙了 看到了嗎? 又在上面紋了玫瑰 來蓋住它
And the work is sloppy. See that? They put the rose over it to cover it up.
- 是啊 我看到了 - 沒錯 那個紋得可不專業
- Yeah,i see that. - Yeah,that wasn't done professionally.
更像是在監獄堹儐
More like it was done in jail.
要是他坐過牢 那就能解釋為什麼 50歲的不明疑犯 直到40才開始殺人
If he did time, that would explain how a 50-year-old unsub doesn't start killing until he's 40.
這夥計是個殺人犯?
This dude's a killer?
還有 為什麼服刑後 強姦犯會變成殺手
And why rapists become killers after they've been in prison.
他們學會了不留人證
They learn not to leave a witness.
Garcia可以用生物識別程序追蹤這個
Garcia can track this through the biometric recognition program.
我貌似是沒機會見 這位掛掉的老兄了吧?
So,there's,like,no chance of me seeing the dead dude,right?
別想了
None.
嘿P.G. 我待會兒會給你 發一張紋身的照片
Hey,p.G.,i'm gonna send you a photograph of a tattoo.
你知道嗎 他背後的空白處 讓他跟"圖案人"一模一樣
You know,that empty space on his back makes him exactly like "the illustrated man."
- 我以為圖案人是紋滿全身的 - 書上是這樣
- I thought he was covered completely. - In the book.
但在電影 他背上有一塊空白 你可以借此看到未來
In the movie, there's an open spot on his back, so you can see the future.
Rossi和Prentiss認為他可能曾服刑
Rossi and prentiss think he may have done time
- 某處紋身可能是在牢堹儐 - 這可能性挺大的
- and that one of the tattoos may have been done in prison. - That's a good bet.
我已經讓Garcia在生物識別數據庫 檢索所有的資料
I've got garcia running everything through the biometrics database.
生物識別?
Biometrics?
是 堶接n記了 所有囚犯和他們的紋身
Yeah,it catalogues all the prison inmates and their tattoos.
有每個囚犯的紋身細節圖
They have detailed photos of every one on every inmate.
- 出什麼事了? - 閉嘴
- What happened? - Shut up.
拜託 坐下 你可以告訴我啊
Please,sit down. You can tell me.
我們可以坐下來... 這事我們可以談談的 我們可以...
We can sit down and-- we can talk about this.We could--
等等! 拜託 我們能談談嗎? 求你了
wait! Please. Can we please talk?
我爸爸一定擔心死我了
My dad has to be so worried about me.
你就沒有爸爸嗎?
Don't you have a father?
- 我什麼人也沒有了 - 求你
- I don't have anyone anymore. - Please.
在他回來之前 就放我走吧
Just let me go before he comes back.
他不會回來了
He's not coming back.
什麼? 等等
What? Wait.
- 你可以放我走的 - 什麼?
- You can let me go. - What?
我...我不會告訴任何人發生了什麼的
It's just-- i won't tell anyone what happened.
我保證 我不會跟任何人說
I promise i won't tell anyone.
你不會跟任何人說?
You won't tell anyone?
我知道你也很怕他
i know you're afraid of him,too.
你不會跟任何人說 是因為 你根本不會活著離開這個房間
You're not going to tell anyone because you're never leaving this room alive.
對不起 真對不起
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
我從來都不害怕他 我愛他
I was never afraid of him. I loved him.
為他 我會做任何事 我為他做了一切
I would do anything, i did anything for him.
他是我的傑作
He was my masterpiece.
你流血了!
You're bleeding!
她會用她的生命來償還
She will pay with her life.
接待完這最後一位客人 就可以填滿藝術收藏堻怮嶊漯臟鴗F
Once i'm done with this newest guest, i'll be able to fill in the last space in my art collection.
最後的空位...最後的空位...  最後的空位...
The last space... Last space... Last space...
不不不 那不對
No,no,no, that's not right.
- 嘿夥計們 那不是唯一空白的地方 - 你什麼意思?
- Hey,guys,it isn't the only blank space. - What do you mean?
- 他胸口 我們推測本該紋Rebecca的地方 - 怎麼了?
- The spot on his chest where we assumed Rebecca's portrait would go-- - yeah?
在日記  他談到填滿最後的空位
in the journal he talks about filling in the last space,
- 一旦填滿 藝術收藏便完整了 - 還有呢?
- how once he does that the artwork will be complete. - And?
那不是唯一空白的地方
It isn't the only blank space.
在他背上 那棵樹的中間 有一大塊空的地方
In his back,in the middle of that tree is a giant open spot.
既然不是填滿"最後的空位" 為何要說完成藝術品呢?
Why would he talk about completing the artwork when he hasn't?
- 我得再看看那具屍體 - 我跟你一起去
- I need to see the body again. - I'll go with you.
我打電話給驗屍官  告訴他你們馬上就到
I'll call the M.E. And let him know you're on your way.
Garcia?
我通過形態追蹤系統 檢索了被蓋的紋身
I ran the covered tattoo through the morpho tracking system.
告訴我有成果啊 寶貝兒
Tell me you got something,babe.
Emily 我正要說呢 別搶我詞
Emily,don't get ahead of my dramatic telling.
我分析了顏色 設計 還有質地
I analyzed color,design, and texture.
它有95%的可能 出自東北部的四家主要監獄之一
There's a 95% chance it is from one of 4 major institutions in the northeastern prison system.
一系列失蹤案是從2000年開始 從未間斷 於是我追溯到那一年
The string of missings began unbroken from 2000, so i went back from that year,
找到個53人有類似的前臂紋身
found 53 similar tattoos on forearms.
其中 有10人於2000年之前出獄 謝謝 晚安
Of those 53,10 were released prior to 2000. Thank you and good night.
你太棒了
You are amazing.
這十個埵 有定了罪的強姦犯嗎?
Of the 10, any convicted rapists?
4個
4.
他們中有人可以追溯到塔拉哈西嗎?
Do any of them trace back to tallahassee?
沒有
None.
- 於是最終我還是一無所獲 - Bob
- So ultimately i have nada. - Bob.
哦 那傢伙 那個租房子的傢伙 他的名字...叫Bob...
Oh,the guy,his name, the guy who rented the property, just bob.
好的好的 我這埵陪 Robert Matthew Burke 1991年定罪
Ok,ok.I have a robert matthew burke, convicted in 1991,
因強姦入獄8年 1999年10月獲釋
8 years for rape, released october of '99.
而那些失蹤案是從2000年開始的
And the missings began in 2000.
Garcia 提醒我 永遠別費勁兒躲你
Garcia,remind me never to try to hide from you.
就死了這條心吧 我的朋友
Perish the thought,mon ami.
Hotch 我們查到名字了
Hotch,we got the name.
- 不明嫌犯叫Robert Matthew Burke - Burke?
- The unsub's name is robert matthew burke. - Burke?
你認識他?
You know him?
Burke 是啊 我認得這個名字 該死的!
Burke. Yeah. I know the name. Damn it!
他是登記在案的性犯罪者 在弗吉尼亞還有前科
He's a registered sex offender. He's an ex-con out of virginia.
Rebecca不見的那晚 他在州立大學附近 吃了一張交通罰單 他是我的疑犯之一
He got a traffic ticket near fsu the night rebecca disappeared. He's one of my suspects.
過去三周 我去過好幾次他的公寓  一直試圖詢問他
I--i went to his apartment, i don't know,a couple times in the past 3 weeks to try to interview him,
但都沒能見到他
but i could never catch up with him.
他知道你在找他嗎?
Did he know you were looking for him?
是啊 我跟他通過電話
Well,yeah,i talked to him on the phone.
他約好週一來這堥訪並提供DNA採樣
He's scheduled to come down for an interview and a dna swab on monday.
這就是變化的地方 他知道被抓只是時間問題
That's what changed. He knew it was only a matter of time before you caught up to him.
而他絕不要再回監獄了
And he wasn't about to go back to prison.
- 你有他的住址嗎? - 有的
- Do you have his address? - Yeah.
哦 我的上帝! 哦 我的上帝!
Oh,my god! Oh,my god!
出問題了 出問題了
Something's wrong. Something's wrong.
卸掉我的鏈子
Unchain me.
卸掉我的鏈子 我會幫你的
Unchain me and i will help you.
我不傻
I am not stupid.
你的寶寶需要幫助
Your baby needs help.
等等! 你不能...這項圈....
Wait! You can't-- the collar.
你幫我...然後我會放你走的
You help me and i'll let you go.
好的 好的 好的
Ok. Ok. Ok.
FBI!
Fbi!
該死
Damn it.
如果這些紋身是某種迷戀 他能從背後的紋身得到什麼享受?
If these tattoos are a fetish, what enjoyment does he get out of the ones on his back?
他連看都看不到它們
He can't even see them.
你知道嗎? 這埵麻I兒東西 我能摸出來墨跡的凸起
You know what? There's something here. I can feel the raised ink.
你有紫光燈掃瞄儀嗎? 謝了
Do you have a black light scanner? Thanks.
就在那 摸摸看
Right there. Feel that.
- 是啊 那是什麼? - 謝了
- Yeah,what is that? - Thanks.
我在書上看過 用隱形墨水刺青 這樣就沒人能看見了
I've read about this. Tattoos put on with invisible ink so that no one can see them.
哦 天啊
Oh,man.
你能...把燈關了嗎? 謝了
Can you,uh,turn the lights down? Thanks.
瞧 那兒也有
Look,there's one over here,too.
它們都連接到臉上
They're all connected to the faces.
- 最後通向那塊留白 - 那是什麼?
- They lead to the blank spot. - What is that?
是子宮堛滬L兒
It's an embryo in a womb.
共犯是個女人 懷了他們的孩子
The partner's a woman, and they're having a baby.
天吶!
Oh,my god!
好多血 我在幹什麼啊
There's more blood. I don't know what i'm doing.
止不住啊 我該怎麼辦! 還在流
It won't stop. It won't stop. I don't know what to do! It won't stop.I don't--
幫我
help me.
她有沒有生產?
Do we know if she had the baby yet?
他的紋身都標了日期 那個胎兒沒有
The tattoos have dates, the embryo doesn't.
在紋身和日記堣暾螺ㄚ頇藆X 記載了綁架的日期
Dating is prominent in the tattoos and the journals and they're calendrical in their abductions.
寶寶的生日肯定也非常重要
It's hard to believe their baby's birthdate wouldn't be exceedingly important to them.
所以她可能還沒生
Then she's probably still pregnant.
他沒和孕婦一起住在這兒 這是只有男性居住的單人間
Well,he didn't live here with a pregnant woman. This is a males-only sro.
反正她肯定有別的地方住
No,she has to have a house,anyway.
你們怎麼知道的?
How do you know that?
每個受害人都被他們關了一年 不可能是在單間公寓
They kept these women for a year each. It wasn't in a one-room apartment.
大家都回來 我們要更新側寫 縮小搜查範圍
Everyone get back here. We need to update the profile and narrow the search.
用力 用力啊!
Push. Push. Push! Push!
差不多了 繼續使勁
It's almost-- it's almost there. Just keep pushing.
- 我不行了 - 看見頭了!
- I can't. - I see the head!
再來一次 好了!
One more time, that's it!
- 請... 告訴我是個女孩 - 什麼?
- Please... Tell me it's a girl. - What?
千萬別是男孩
It can't be a boy. Please.
你生了兒子
you have a son.
怎麼能是個男孩
It can't be a boy.
不能是男孩 把他抱走
It can't be a boy. Get it away from me.
- 你得照顧他 - 我不要
- You need to take him. - I don't want it.
他會像他們一樣傷害我
He'll hurt me like they all do.
我以為我懷的是個女孩
I felt for sure i was having a girl.
不要啊! 你得送我出去
No,no,no! You gotta get me out of here.
你得帶我離開這兒!
You have to get me out of here!
來人吶! 救命! 救救我們!
Help us! Help us! Help us!
****
乖乖
**********
沒事的
It's ok.
我們可以利用共犯懷孕了這一點
The partner being pregnant can help us.
讓Garcia查查她的醫療就診記錄
We should have garcia try and find her through doctor visits or medical records.
他是個黑戶 所以她應該也一樣
He basically lived off the grid, which means she did,too.
從他們給受害者拍的照片來看
Judging by the photographs of what they did to the victims,
他們確實與世隔絕
it's safe to say they live in isolation.
他那麼仇恨女性 卻還是和她合作
We've seen his hatred for women,and yet he teams up with her.
什麼樣的女人能讓他有所轉變?
What kind of woman could change him?
你覺得他們是監獄婸{識的嗎?
You think they met in prison?
Garcia已經查遍了 沒有女性探望他
Garcia already went through all of that. He had no female visitors.
那監獄工作人員 醫生或者牧師呢?
What about prison staff, doctors,religious volunteers?
我們查了他監禁期間的所有傭工
We went through a long list of all the vendors who were there during his incarceration.
他們都不在塔拉哈西了
None of them resurfaced in tallahassee.
什麼樣的女人會到監獄堨h 愛上一個強姦犯?
What kind of a woman would go to a prison to fall in love with a rapist?
體質弱 感情脆弱 喜歡暴力男
Someone vulnerable, emotionally fragile, drawn to violent men.
是某個人讓她變成那樣的 經典虐待循環
Someone in her life made her that way. Classic abuse cycle.
可能就是她要去看的人?
What if that's who she was there to visit?
值得一試
It's worth a try.
小甜甜
My sweet.
你有剛才那個監獄的訪客記錄嗎?
Hey,you know the visitor logs from the prison we looked at?
- 早有準備 - 很好 幫我查一下約見記錄
- Still have them at the ready. - Ok,great. I need you to check dates for me.
Burke在押的時候 有沒有去探訪其他囚犯的女性
Were there any women who visited another inmate while burke was there
在Burke出獄之後就再也不去了?
but then suddenly stopped visiting when burke was released?
好 等會兒告訴你
Ok,let me hit you back.
沒事了 不會有事的
It's ok. It's ok.
我幫不了你!
I can't help you!
不會有事的...
It's ok...
開動腦筋了 夥計們
Rev your engines,guys.
從92年到95年 Juliet Monroe 平均每年去看他父親一兩次
Juliet monroe went to visit her father in prison once or twice a year from '92 to '95.
- 他因為什麼入獄? - 強姦
- What was he in for? - Rape.
她是他第一個受害者
And she was his primary victim.
他強姦了她 她還每年都去看他?
He raped her and she still went to visit him every year?
她在重複成長過程中的週期
She's repeating the cycle she grew up with.
從95年到97年她開始每月都去看他
Yeah. And she went from visiting him once or twice a year to once a month from '95 to '97.
正是Burke服刑的時候
When burke was serving his time for rape.
沒錯 然後98年到99年她每周去一次
Yeah. And then she increased her visits to once a week all through '98 and '99,
直到那年十月為止
until they stopped completely in october of that year.
因為他被放出來了
That's when he was released.
更有力的證據 她在北佛羅里達有一所房子
And if you want me to slip you some convincers, she owns a house in northern florida.
Garcia 給我們地址
Garcia,get us the address.
我和Rossi堵前面 你們側面包抄
Rossi and i will take the front. Take the side.
走
Go.
在這兒! 快來啊 我們在這兒
In here! Please help. In here! In here.
寶寶 寶寶
The baby. The baby.
她死了
She's--she's dead.
好了 給我寶寶 把寶寶給我 好勒
All right, give me the baby. Give me the baby. I got him.
沒事了
You're gonna be all right.
救我
Help me.
Becky 你還好嗎?
Becky,are you ok?
我只想回家 我想回家
I just want to go home. I just want to go home.
你可以回家了 親愛的 沒事了
Yeah,you're going home, honey. You're going home. It's ok.
我通知你家長了 他們會去醫院接你
So,i talked to your parents. They're gonna meet you at the hospital,ok?
寶寶還好嗎?
Is the baby ok?
嗯 他在另一輛救護車上
Oh,yeah,he's-- he's in another ambulance.
他以後怎麼辦?
What's gonna happen to him?
別擔心 我們會好好照顧他的
Hey,don't you worry. We're gonna take real good care of him,ok?
小姐 咱們該走了
Ma'am,we should get going.
保重 會好起來的
Take care. It'll be ok.
她沒事了吧?
She gonna be ok?
我肯定她會沒事的
I wouldn't bet against anybody who survived what she did.
你怎麼樣?
How about you?
我嘛 不會受影響的
Oh,yeah,you know, nothing's gonna affect me.
要不是你一再堅持 我們也不會來的
You know,we wouldn't be here if you hadn't worked the case as hard as you did.
怎麼會?
How's that?
在她失蹤的地方 無視交通罰單是常事
It would have been an easy thing to miss a routine traffic ticket in the area she disappeared.
你一直在施壓
You kept the pressure on.
查清了9宗殺人案 救回了Becky
You cleared 9 homicides and you brought becky home.
表現不錯 警探
It's impressive work, detective.
謝謝
Thanks.
三張牌
3 cards,please.
給這位女士三張牌
3 cards for the lady.
我自己要一張
And i'm gonna take one card.
一張 小博士你是在湊順牌還是同花?
One card. A straight or a flush, dr. Reid,what are you trying to fill in?
抽一張牌湊到五張順牌的幾率是5比1
Well,considering the odds of filling in an open-ended straight with one card are 5-to-1 against,
而一張牌抽中同花的幾率是4.5比1
while a one-card flush draw is more like 4.5-to-1,
我想你會說 如果我夠聰明的話 就應該湊同花
i guess you'd say if i was smart, i'm drawing to a flush.
這些我全押上
I think i'm gonna go all in on this.
你到底是……?
So,are you?
- 我湊同花 還是我聰明? - 隨便
- Am i drawing to a flush, or am i smart? - Either.
不可否認我是個天才 但是
Well,i'm-- i'm provably a genius, but,uh,actually,
我手堿O三帶二 三個8帶一對6
i was drawing to a full house. 8s over 6s.
- 差點忘了你是賭城來的 - 是耶
- I always forget you're from vegas. - Yup.
哎哎 慢著 我也有
Ooh,i'm sorry, not so fast. I,too,have a boat.
三個J帶一對3
Jacks over 3s.
你抽了三張牌就三帶二了? 那可是100比1的幾率啊
You drew 3 cards to a full house? That's like 100-to-1 against.
97比1 你凹凸了
97-to-1. Looks like you're out.
Prentiss 贏了就有罪?
Hey,prentiss. Sin to win.
- 啊 什麼? - 說吧 我想知道
- I'm sorry,what? - Come on,now, i gotta know.
大西洋城的"贏了就有罪"週末 到底是啥?
What the hell is a sin to win weekend in atlantic city?
Derek 不是瞧不起你啊
Derek,i have a tremendous amount of respect for you,
但是有些問題你覺得不吐不快
but there's some questions that if you have to ask them,
可答案你又接受不了
it means you probably couldn't handle the answer.
這女人真讓人摸不透
There is a whole other side to that woman.
- 人家從來沒輸過 - 簡直是百變嬌娃
- I never lose. - A whole other side.
我知道環境比遺傳更重要
I know environment plays a bigger role than genetics
決定孩子的將來
when it comes to determining a child's future,
可那個小孩 他的父母
but that baby,i mean, both the parents.
- 有多少連環殺手有孩子的? - 很多
- How many other serial killers had kids? - A lot.
曼森有10個還是11個
Manson has like 10 or 11 children.
- Albert Fish有6個 - Gary Ridgeway有一個兒子
- Albert fish had 6. - Gary ridgeway had a son.
Fred和Rosemary West在養著 7個孩子的家堭了10個女人
Fred and rosemary west had 7 children living in the home where they killed 10 women.
包括他們自己的一個孩子
Including one of the children.
- 所以 那個小孩不會有事的? - 基本不會 如果他在好人家長大
- Ok,so,the baby's gonna be ok? - Most likely. If he grows up in a good home.
受到關愛和悉心照料
Loved,cared for.
很好
Good.
甘地曾說 "孩子們不會 為繼承而來的罪惡所影響
Gandhi said, "i have seen children successfully surmount the effects "of an evil inheritance.
因為靈魂的本質是純淨的"
"that is due to purity being an inherent attribute of the soul."
犯罪心理 第五季 第20集 千言萬語
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode20 A Thousand Words